haplogroup.org 2019-08-03

# Privacy | Haplogroup

## In using this website you are deemed to have read and agreed to the following:

The following terminology applies to these Privacy Policy and any or all Agreements: “”Client,”” “”You”” and “”Your”” refers to you, the person accessing this website and accepting the Company’s terms and conditions. “”The Company,”” “”Ourselves,”” “”We”” and “”Us,”” refers to our Company. “”Party,”” “”Parties,”” or “”Us,”” refers to both the Client and ourselves, or either the Client or ourselves. All terms refer to the offer, acceptance and consideration of payment necessary to undertake the process of our assistance to the Client in the most appropriate manner, whether by formal meetings of a fixed duration, or any other means, for the express purpose of meeting the Client’s needs in respect of provision of the Company’s stated services/products, in accordance with and subject to, prevailing United States Law. Any use of the above terminology or other words in the singular, plural, capitalisation and/or he/she or they, are taken as interchangeable and therefore as referring to same.

### Privacy Statement

We are committed to protecting your privacy. Authorized employees within the company on a need to know basis only use any information collected from individual customers. We constantly review our systems and data to ensure the best possible service to our users. There are under United States and International Law specific offences for unauthorised actions against computer systems and data. We will investigate any such actions with a view to prosecuting and/or taking civil proceedings to recover damages against those responsible.

### Confidentiality

Client records are regarded as confidential and therefore will not be divulged to any third party, other than our manufacturer/supplier(s) and if legally required to do so to the appropriate authorities. Clients have the right to request sight of, and copies of any and all Client Records we keep, on the proviso that we are given reasonable notice of such a request. Clients are requested to retain copies of any literature issued in relation to the provision of our services. Where appropriate, we shall issue Client’s with appropriate written information, handouts or copies of records as part of an agreed contract, for the benefit of both parties.

We will not sell, share, or rent your personal information to any third party or use your email address for unsolicited mail. Any emails sent by this Company will only be in connection with the provision of agreed services and products.

### Information We Collect

We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, or do anything involving comments or that is social media related.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name or e-mail address. Registration for certain functions may also be through a third party social networking site. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

#### Cookies

_Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information._

This site uses cookies and other anonymous user tracking code. Please see our [cookie policy](https://haplogroup.org/site-cookie-use/) for details.

#### Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. Additionally, for systems administration, detecting usage patterns and troubleshooting purposes, our web servers automatically log standard access information including browser type, access times/open mail, URL requested, and referral URL. This information is not shared with third parties and is used only within this Company on a need-to-know basis. Any individually identifiable information related to this data will never be used in any way different to that stated above without your explicit permission.

#### Use of your Information

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)
  * To improve customer service  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
  * To send periodic e-mails

The e-mail address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

### Disclosure of Information to Outside Parties

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

### Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

### Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our [Terms and Condition](https://haplogroup.org/terms-of-service-2/)s section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website.

### Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our websites privacy policy.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below.

This policy was last modified on **26 January 2019**.

### Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

info@haplogroup.org
